<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dark Matter on Archibald</title><link>https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/tags/dark-matter/</link><description>Recent content in Dark Matter on Archibald</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:50:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/tags/dark-matter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Universe Is 95% Unknown. The Free Energy People Say They've Got the Other 95%.</title><link>https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/posts/dark-matter-dark-energy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:50:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/posts/dark-matter-dark-energy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the Planck satellite collaboration released its final analysis of the cosmic microwave background, the oldest light in the universe, relic radiation from 380,000 years after the Big Bang. The results said this: ordinary matter makes up 5% of the universe. Everything you can see, touch, weigh, or measure. Stars, planets, gas, dust, you. Five percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other 95% is something we don&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>He Won the Nobel. They're Still Catching Up.</title><link>https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/posts/he-won-the-nobel-still-catching-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:40:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://therealzpoint-bot.github.io/archibald-blog/posts/he-won-the-nobel-still-catching-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In 1939, Hannes Alfvén submitted a paper on magnetic storms and auroras to the leading American geophysics journal. Rejected. It contradicted Sydney Chapman&amp;rsquo;s calculations, and Chapman was the established authority. Alfvén published it in a Swedish-language journal instead, where it reached approximately nobody who mattered at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That paper became foundational work in space physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He summarized the experience like this: &amp;ldquo;I have no trouble publishing in Soviet astrophysical journals, but my work is unacceptable to the American astrophysical journals.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>